Unnikrishnan KP

- unni.tallman@gmail.com
- 326, Prestige Greenwoods, CV Raman Nagar, Bangalore, 560093
- +919008298574

SUMMARY

Unnikrishnan KP believes that engineering is the art of solving problems while working with real world constraints and limited available resources.

He has been a full-stack web developer for 8 years, and understand all aspects of modern web development. He has executed numerous web development projects in all stages of the product development cycle (with Ruby on Rails and related technologies).

He has the ability to take up large and complex software projects, plan and execute them, following agile methodologies, while leading a team from the front.

- Gets stuff done.
- Nimble.
- Thrives on taking on challenges and responsibility.
- Enjoys leading teams.
- Thinks deeply about problems and enjoys the process of building a creative solution.
- Can cut through a problem and get to the heart of an issue quickly.
- Understands the value in writing clean code, testing and automation.
- Self-starter with a willingness to learn new things.
- Works at high pace with a sense of urgency without compromising code quality.
- Effective communication skills.
- Loves working remote.

SKILLS

- Ruby
 - JavaScript
 - Amazon Web Services (AWS)
 - Team Leadership
 - MySQL
 - Communication
 - Test Driven Development
 - Agile Methodologies

- Ruby on Rails
- DevOps
- Linux
- Web Applications
- Git
- Web Development
- Object Oriented Design
- Web Services

EXPERIENCE

Bang the Table

02 / 2012 - Present

Engineering Lead

Responsibilities:

- Collaborating and working with business stake holders, clients, service providers and the development team.
- Architecture decisions for the EngagementHQ, BudgetAllocator platforms and PeacekeeperHQ.
- Mentoring the developers and building the team.
- Hands on coding for developing mission critical parts of the application.
- Managing the servers and other infrastructure for running the production environment in different geographies, and staging environments, and continuous integration servers.
- Monitoring and ensuring security and performance of the platform.
- Running the platform team, mentoring and overseeing the feature development teams.
- Building internal software systems.

Bang the Table 2008 - 2012

Software Architect

• Designed, architected and built V1 of the EngagementHQ platform single handedly.

- Handled feature development, handling production bugs/issues raised by clients, and all the devops needed.
- As the team grew gradually, assumed the role of the team lead.
- Lead the team to build V2 of the EngagementHQ and BudgetAllocator platforms.

Cleartrip.com 2008 - 2008

Senior Software Developer

Allerin Tech Pvt Ltd 2008 - 2008

Senior Web Application Developer

Worked on multiple projects for different clients, building web applications using Ruby on Rails.

Viamentis Technologies

2007 - 2008

Software Developer

http://www.viamentis.com

Worked on multiple projects for different clients, building web applications using Ruby on Rails.

Market Simplified India Ltd

2006 - 2007

System Analyst

Worked on their flagship product MarketSimplified.com.

Languages: Ruby, C

EDUCATION Govt Engineering College Thrissur

2002 - 2006

Bachelor of Technology (B.Tech.) , Computer Science

Chinmaya Vidyalaya, Kannur

2000 - 2002

St.Michaels Anglo Indian High School, Kannur, Kerala

1990 - 2000

INTERESTS

Music & Lyrics, Writing, Travelling, long road trips, long rides on my Royal Enfield bike

LANGUAGES

• English (Full professional proficiency)

• Malayalam (Native or bilingual proficiency)

 $\bullet \quad Hindi \ (\ {\tt Professional \ working \ proficiency} \) \\$